<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.6">
			<file name="subclass-mech-pilot.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Mech Pilot" type="Archetype" source="Angus H" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_ARTIFICER_MECH-PILOT">
		<supports>Artificer Specialist</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Mastery of the modern battlefield requires a hybrid approach of technology and magic, and no combat specialist epitomozies this approach better than the mech pilot. Armed and armoured in an enchanted mobile suit, the battle mech is a flexible weapons platform built to be reconfigureable. This allows it to fit into any tactical situation on evolving battlefields. The Mech pilot's bond to their battle mech is critical to their success. The battle mech is attuned to their pilot's magic and strong fluctuations of that power source can cause instability, desyncronisation and mission failure. However, a Mech Pilot with mind and mech united can become an unstoppable force.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_TACTICAL_ARRAY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_BATTLE_MECH" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_OVERDRIVE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_AIR_SUPREMACY" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>A Mech Pilot is an expert in any situation, provided they are prepared.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_TACTICAL_ARRAY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_BATTLE_MECH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_OVERDRIVE" level="9" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_AIR_SUPREMACY" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Tactical Array" type="Archetype Feature" source="Angus H" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_TACTICAL_ARRAY">
		<description>
			<p>You can adjust your armour for a given combat situation. When you create your battle mech, choose one of the following modes: Hellion, Valkyrie or Titan. The mode you choose gives you special benefits while you wear the battle mech, and determines its properties as armour per the Battle Mech Armour table. You can change your battle mech's mode whenever you finish a short or long rest, provided you have tinker's tools in hand.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="true">
			<description>Choose Hellion, Valkyrie or Titan. You can change mode every short or long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mech Pilot Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ALCHEMIST_ALCHEMIST_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, you always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Mech Pilot Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don’t count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">MECH PILOT SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Artificer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>magic missle, shield</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>gust of wind, shatter</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>lightning bolt, thunder step</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>fire shield, storm sphere</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>steel wind strike, teleportation circle</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="true">
			<description>You always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Mech Pilot Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don’t count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSLE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="3" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" spellcasting="Artificer" level="5" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_lIGHTNING_BOLT" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDER_STEP" spellcasting="Artificer" level="9" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STORM_SPHERE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="13" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE" spellcasting="Artificer" level="17" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Battle Mech" type="Archetype Feature" source="Angus H" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_BATTLE_MECH">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, your knowledge of arcane mechanics has allowed you to develop a shophisticated mechanical suit that you pilot into battle. Over the course of a long rest, you can use your tinker's tools to create a battle mech, which functions as a magical suit of armour.</p>
			<p>You gain the following benefits while wearing the battle mech: </p>
			<p class="indent">When you attack with a weapon, you can use your Intelligence modifer, instead of Strength or Dexterity modifer, for the attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent">You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can pusgh, drag, or lift.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain proficiency with martial weapons</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Angus H" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 5th level, you can attack twice, rather than once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice starting at 5th Level</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Overdrive" type="Archetype Feature" source="Angus H" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_OVERDRIVE">
		<description>
			<p>starting at 9th level, you can push your battle mech to its limits. As an action, you can activate your battle mech's Overdrive ability, which grants you effects based on its mode, as shown below. This ability requires a loud vocal component. Once you have used a mode's Overdrive abilty, you cannot use that mode's Overdrive ability again until you have finished a long rest</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Hellion. You gain advantage on your ranged weapon attacks for 1 minute</li>
				<li>Valkyrie. You cast the haste spell on yourself without verbal, somatic, or material components and without requiring your concentration.</li>
				<li>Titan. You cast the enlarge/reduce spell on yourself without verbal, somatic, or material components and without requiring your concentration. While you are under the effect of the spell, you gain temporary hit points equal to your artificer level at the end of each turn. When you use your Rebuff feature against a target, you can deal 1d6 thunder damage to every target of your choice within 10ft of it.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>From 9th level, use this abilty to gain effects dependent on your battle mech mode.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Air Supremacy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Angus H" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MECHPILOT_AIR_SUPREMACY">
		<description>
			<p>By 15th level, Your battle mech can take to the skies and unleash its full potential. You have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed. Additionally, your battle mech gains benefits based on its mode, as shown below.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Hellion. When you hit a target with a ranged weapon attack, you can deal an extra 1d4 cold, fire, lightning or thunder damage (your choice) to that target.</li>
				<li>Valkyrie. When you use your Blitz feature, you instead deal an extra 1d8 lightning damage for every 10ft you move in a straight line toward a target before hitting it with a weapong attack, to a maximum of 4d8</li>
				<li>Titan. When you use your Rebuff feature, to push a creature away from you, you can instead choose to knock them prone.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				<li>Hellion. When you hit a target with a ranged weapon attack, you can deal an extra 1d4 cold, fire, lightning or thunder damage (your choice) to that target.</li>
				<li>Valkyrie. When you use your Blitz feature, you instead deal an extra 1d8 lightning damage for every 10ft you move in a straight line toward a target before hitting it with a weapong attack, to a maximum of 4d8</li>
				<li>Titan. When you use your Rebuff feature, to push a creature away from you, you can instead choose to knock them prone.</li>
			</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
